恕我直言 威震天陛下
If it pleases you, Lord Megatron
现在声波在破译剩余的铁堡密码
once Soundwave discovers a means of decoding the remainder of the Iacon database
我们知道他定能手到擒来
-- as we know he will, I would suggest the deployment of an underutilized asset.
同时我提醒您还有一种资源未被充分利用
什么资源 毒蜘蛛？
And what asset would that be, Airachnid?
我相信我卓越的侦查技能
I believe that my superior tracking skills would expedite
可以加快您寻找其余遗物的步伐
your quest to recover the remaining relics.
我知道了
Noted.
英明的决断 我的陛下
You are a gracious audience, My Lord.
声波
Soundwave.
我该信任她吗？
Remind me of her trustworthiness.
“我们必须做出长远的打算 无需考虑威震天了”
"I believe we must consider the possibility of a future... without Megatron."
骇翼
Dreadwing.
随时听从您的吩咐 威震天陛下
I am at your beck and call, Lord Megatron.
我要交给你一个本该由我亲自督办的任务
I wish to entrust you with a task I would normally reserve for myself.
这也是证明你能胜任副官的最好机会
That is, if you wish to prove yourself worthy of becoming my first lieutenant.
这个职位目前属于毒蜘蛛
That post belongs to Airachnid.
我们会怀念她的
She will be missed.
我建议你最好带上后援 她可相当棘手
And I suggest you bring backup. She can be a handful.
特别是被逼入绝境的时候…
Especially when cornered...
难道只有我认为威震天在小题大作吗？
Am I the only one here who considers this to be overkill on Lord Megatron's part?
我是说 他居然派遣两个得力部下
I mean, dispatching two of his most proficient warriors
去勘探一个未经开采的能量矿
to track down one unconfirmed Energon spike.
威震天认为我和骇翼就足以完成任务
Megatron knows me and Dreadwing here will get the job done.
事实上 我说的得力部下是我和骇翼
Actually, I was referring to Dreadwing and myself.
呃…
Eghh...
打击 专注你的任务
Breakdown, remain on task.
我们必须齐心协力
This must be a unified effort.
没错 打击
Indeed, Breakdown.
我知道你一只眼看不惯我一双眼
I know we've never seen eyes to eye
不过你还有补丁嘛
but that doesn't mean we can't patch things up.
呃 受够了！
That's it!
别这样！
Don't!
打击！别干傻事 先救我出来！
Breakdown, don't be a fool. Release me.
哈哈哈
Hahahahaha...
小菜一碟…
Easy prey.
打击 你怎么样了？打击!
Breakdown, what is your status? Breakdown!
机械党一号报告塞拉斯 我们有了意外的发现
MECH 1 to Silas. Our maneuvers have yielded unexpected results...
还是个老相识…
and a familiar face.
我居然沦落到靠捡能量碎片来度日？
How is it that I have been reduced to seeking Energon scraps merely to survive?
机器昆虫？在地球上！
An Insecticon, on Earth?
嘿 你个捡垃圾的！
You there, scavenger!
把那块能量给我
Deliver that Energon to me.
你胆敢对你的上司如此不敬？
You dare turn your back on a superior life-form?
我是红蜘蛛指挥官！
I am commander Starscream.
好吧！留着那块能量吧！
Fine! Keep the Energon.
希望它噎死你！
I hope you choke on it.
很好 奴隶 到我这儿来
Yes, minion, approach me.
服从我
Obey me.
朝拜我
Worship me.
不用这么客气
You shouldn't have.
什么？你拒绝了一个指挥官
What?! You reject a commander
却对那种小人物奴颜婢膝？
but grovel at the feet of that wretch?
红蜘蛛 别愁眉苦脸的
Starscream. Don't get your turbines in a twist.
毕竟 这个怪兽和我有些亲缘关系
After all, the beast and I are somewhat related.
甚至可以说 我们是心灵相通的
You might even say we are of... one mind.
你为什么会在这儿？
Why are you here?
霸天虎从来不会回到开采完毕的矿区！
Decepticons never return to stripped mines.
你并非唯一一个回来找能量的流亡霸天虎
You are not the only rogue Decepticon in need of Energon.
那是和汽车人战斗受的伤？
Was it a run-in with the Autobots?
还是威震天又邀请你参加他的“实地考察”了？
Or did Megatron invite you on one of his field trips?
威震天在忙别的事
Megatron was otherwise engaged.
不过你可以见到他的新仆人
But you should see his lackey.
你看 毒蜘蛛
You know, Airachnid
我们同为流亡者 应先将分歧放在一边
as fellow outcasts, we should consider putting aside our differences.
我们有了这种听从你指挥的生物
With this creature under your control
我们可以用他去了结威震天
... and at our disposal, we might employ it to terminate Megatron
夺取霸天虎的控制权
allowing us to rule the Decepticons.
一起？
Together?
我们只需要将威震天引到这儿
We would simply need to lure Megatron here
让他远离他的“支援系统”
away from his support systems
这样我们也许能逮到他…
so that we might catch him...
趁他放松警惕之时？
With his guard down?
一个迷人的计划
An intriguing proposal...
不过我并不希望与你共同统治霸天虎
If ruling Decepticons or spending any length of time with you
甚至是与你相处…
were of the slightest interest to me.
什么？啊！
That... agh? huh!
当然 你给了我一个打败威震天的机会
Of course, you had me at "terminate Megatron."
复仇会是甜蜜的…
Payback would be sweet.
总之你说了算
However you wish to spin it.
我需要确认我的刺客能胜任这份差事
I would need to ensure my assassin is up to the task.
也许需要一个测试…
Perhaps a test run is in order.
什么？我以为我们是同伴！
What? I thought we were partners.
剖开他！
Eviscerate him.
这是什么？
What is it?
一个含有嵌入信息的高频信号
A high-frequency signal with an embedded message.
又是他？
Again?
红蜘蛛 我有你最感兴趣的情报
Starscream. "I have obtained information of extreme interest to you."
带医疗箱过来
"Bring medical kit."
安全！
Clear!
快说！
Make it fast.
毒蜘蛛也成了像我一样的流亡霸天虎
It would appear that, like myself, Airachnid has gone rogue.
这对我们有什么用？！
What's it to us?
她计划报复威…
She is planning to retaliate against Meg...
…人类！
Eh... mankind.
我可以向你提供她目前的位置
I can provide you with her current location.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
为什么？
Why wouldn't you?
我曾经告诉你霸天虎太空桥的位置
I directed you to the location of the decepticon space bridge
你才救回了奥利安・派克斯 对吧？
so you could rescue Orion Pax, didn't I?
是的 但随后你就帮机械党偷走了大黄蜂的变形齿轮
Yeah, but then you helped M.E.C.H. steal Bumblebee's T-cog.
是吗？但他又抢了回去 不是吗？
So? He got it back, didn't he?
我承认！与邪恶的人类合作
I admit... aligning myself with those vile humans
是个巨大的错误
was a colossal error in judgment.
但我孤立无援！我做的一切都是为了生存！
But I am alone. I do what I must to survive.
而且我为此付出了代价
But I have paid the price.
现在我失去了自己的变形齿轮！
I am now the one missing his T-cog.
你飞不起来了？
You're grounded?
所以对你们来说毫无威胁
Thus of little, if any, threat to you.
但是 毒蜘蛛和她的机器昆虫打算…
But Airachnid and her Insecticon intend to...
机器昆虫？！在这里？
An Insecticon?! Here?
怎么会？！
How?
本来我也想问个明白…
Well, I would have asked.
…但当时我急于从一个小缝隙里面挤过去
but I was too busy squeezing through a narrow crevice
以防止那只毒虫啃掉我的腿！
trying to keep the vermin from chewing my leg off!
而毒蜘蛛就在一旁看着…
While Airachnid watched.
我们已经搞清了为什么无法定位打击的信号
The reason for our inability to locate Breakdown's signal is all too clear.
但为何你连他的残骸都没能带回来？
But how is it that you were unable to recover his remains?
那是什么？
What is it?
想听听打击的最新消息吗？
Heard from Breakdown lately?
追踪信号
Trace the communication.
亲爱的威震天
Megatron, truly.
你居然派一个白痴喽罗 妄图消灭一个高级军官
You sent simple henchman to terminate a high-ranking officer.
我本以为你只会把这份殊荣留给自己…
I thought you reserved that honor for yourself.
这是个挑衅！
Is that a challenge?
一个邀请
An invitation.
毫无疑问 既然声波正在追踪这个信号
And since Soundwave is no doubt tracing this signal
那你知道在哪里能找到我…
you know where to find me.
我去去就来
I'll be back.
请允许我伴您同去
Allow me to accompany you.
我已经给过你机会了
You already had your chance.
红蜘蛛提供的坐标位于一座废弃的霸天虎矿区
The coordinates Starscream provided are within an abandoned Decepticon mine.
等等 你刚刚修好他 就打发他走了？
Hold on. You just fixed him up and sent him on his way?
不然你想怎么样
What were we supposed to do?
带他回来？
Take him back here?
我不会放弃任何一个追杀毒蜘蛛的机会
Not that I wouldn't jump at any chance to put Airachnid down
但她并非唯一一个杀害我搭档的人
but she isn't the only one who's robbed me of a partner.
当时你不在场 阿尔茜
You weren't there, Arcee.
红蜘蛛虚弱至极 毫无抵抗能力
Starscream was weak, defenseless.
此外机器昆虫的情报具有战略价值
And learning of the Insecticon could prove highly tactical.
根据以往的经验 红蜘蛛的情报是可靠的
Starscream's intel has proved credible in the past.
没错！在他不忙于暗算我们的时候
Sure, when he wasn't busy stabbing us in the back.
眼下我们缺少塞博特恩上的资源
Without the resources we possessed on Cybertron
用来监禁和束缚敌人
we lack ready means of capturing and imprisoning our enemies.
尽管如此 我仍然不能漠视无助的生命
Nonetheless, I do not condone the termination of any defenseless life-form.
您一向雷厉风行
You don't waste time.
你的缓刑期已经到头了！
Your stay of execution has come to an end.
我介绍你们俩认识一下
I will leave you two to get acquainted.
向威震天 你们的主人 鞠躬！
Bow before Megatron, your leader.
我说 鞠躬！
I said, "bow..."
你和你的畜牲给我记住了
You and your beast would do well to remember...
我可是在卡隆的角斗场里杀出来的！
I honed my skills in the pits of Kaon!
谨慎行事
Proceed with extreme caution.
结果他！
Finish him!
喔 小红可没提到威震天！
Whoa. Scream never mentioned Megatron.
看上去是红蜘蛛精心策划了这一幕
It would seem Starscream orchestrated this convergence
设计让他的敌人自相残杀 好坐收渔翁之利
in the hope that all his enemies would destroy each other on his behalf.
我中计了！
And I fell for it.
你可以随意处置威震天的遗骸 毒蜘蛛是我的
Well, you can have whatever's left of Megatron. Airachnid's mine.
阿尔茜 不！
Arcee! No!
你！
You.
今天真是惊喜连连！
So many surprises, today.
这是一个警告 给所有妄图挑衅卡隆角斗士的人！
Let that be a warning to anyone who dares cross a gladiator of Kaon
无论是霸天虎或是汽车人
be they Decepticon...  or Autobot.
我已经无力反抗了 全凭你处置
It would seem that I'm unarmed and at your mercy.
请告诉我擎天柱 你会放我一马吗？
So, tell me, Optimus. Do you intend to take me alive?
或是就此了结恩怨
Or end this here and now?
惊喜总是不断
The surprises never cease.
哦 糟了…
Oh, scrap.
不好!
Scrap!
或许今天我无法熄灭威震天的火种
This may not be the day that I take Megatron's spike
但我可以结果了你…
but it is the day I remove yours.
你说的很对 毒蜘蛛
How right you were, Airachnid.
复仇会是甜蜜的
Payback is sweet.
把威震天交给我们
Deliver Megatron to us
我们会让你们全身而退
and I will allow you to live.
永远不要相信虎子 打爆这个铁桶头！
Never trust a Con. Kick buckethead's bucket!
骇翼 我能信任你吗？
Dreadwing, do I have your word?
我的君王
My liege.
骇翼 也许你会遵守诺言 可我不会
Dreadwing may have given you his word, but I did not.
消灭他们！
Destroy them!
你们胆敢抗命追踪我到此
You disobeyed my orders in following me here.
你会是一个好副官的
You will make a fine first lieutenant.
这可真够刺激的
That was intense.
如果说除了八条腿的我还讨厌什么
Now, if there's one thing I despise nearly as much as eight-leggers
那就是两轮车…
it's two-wheelers.
来吧 动手吧
Go on. Get it over with.
我想起来了 这一幕似曾相识
As I recollect, in a similar predicament.
你留了我一命
you once allowed me to live.
现在我们扯平了
Consider us even.
阿尔茜 你情况如何？
Arcee, what is your status?
还活着 但需要帮助
In need of assist, but alive.
估计毒蜘蛛也一样
And so is Airachnid.
至少威震天除掉了她的害虫
At least Megatron took care of the other bug problem.
红蜘蛛 我发誓要拧下你的脑袋！
Starscream, I vow I will have your head.
原来我的“战士”不过是个前哨！
So, my warrior was merely a scout.